Guide to the Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection, 1885-2012 and undated RL.11612
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection
1885-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pollay, Richard W.
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11612
225.0 Linear Feet
Richard W. Pollay was Professor and Curator of the History of Advertising Archives at the Sauder School of Business, University of British Columbia. Collection includes audiovisual materials in multiple formats (audio and video cassettes, optical discs), clippings of articles and advertisements, pamphlets and other printed material, artifacts and ephemera (including apparel, cups, luggage, playing cards, promotional gifts and samples of tobacco packaging and candy cigarettes), photographs and slides, research reports, corporate documents, depositions and transcripts of court case testimony and other litigation-related materials. Topics include tobacco advertising and deceptive advertising practices; package labeling and health claims; cigarette marketing; manipulation of tar and nicotine levels; "light" and menthol cigarettes; lung cancer and other smoking-related health issues; smoking cessation and anti-smoking initiatives in the United States, Canada and internationally; tobacco industry manufacturing and marketing practices; smoking initiation and teenage and young adult smoking; and marketing of tobacco products to women and minorities. Companies represented include American Tobacco, British American Tobacco, Brown & Williamson, Imperial Tobacco, Liggett & Myers, Lorillard, Philip Morris (later Altria), R.J. Reynolds/RJR Nabisco and the Tobacco Institute. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: 800 Audiovisual Materials; 900 Slides; 950 Print Advertising; 1000 Advertising and Marketing; 2000 Pollay Publications and History of Advertising Archives Working Papers; 3000 Notes and Sources for Tobacco Research; 4000 U.S. Government Reports; 5000 Tobacco Control; 6000 Public Relations, Advocacy, Health Promotion; 7000 Corporate Documents; 8000 Litigation and Court Records; 9000 Special Topics; Ephemera (Tobacciana); and 2013 Addition. The numbers in the series titles refer to record group numbers assigned by Pollay in the History of Advertising Archives.
Collection Overview
Collection includes audiovisual materials in multiple formats (audio and video cassettes, optical discs), clippings of articles and advertisements, pamphlets and other printed material, artifacts and ephemera (including apparel, cups, luggage, playing cards, promotional gifts and samples of tobacco packaging and candy cigarettes), photographs and slides, research reports, corporate documents, depositions and transcripts of court case testimony and other litigation-related materials. Topics include tobacco advertising and deceptive advertising practices; package labeling and health claims; cigarette marketing; manipulation of tar and nicotine levels; "light" and menthol cigarettes; lung cancer and other smoking-related health issues; smoking cessation and anti-smoking initiatives in the United States, Canada and internationally; tobacco industry manufacturing and marketing practices; smoking initiation and teenage and young adult smoking; and marketing of tobacco products to women and minorities. Companies represented include American Tobacco, British American Tobacco, Brown & Williamson, Imperial Tobacco, Liggett & Myers, Lorillard, Philip Morris (later Altria), R.J. Reynolds/RJR Nabisco and the Tobacco Institute. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Biographical / Historical
Richard W. Pollay was Professor and Curator of the History of Advertising Archives at the Sauder School of Business, University of British Columbia. Born 1940, Connecticut; BA 1962 Rensselar Polytechnic; MA 1963, PhD 1970 University of Chicago. Assistant Professor, University of Kansas 1966-1970; Associate Professor 1970, Professor 1986, University of British Columbia.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide, Inc. records
Jean Kilbourne papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic advertisements
Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company records
Sheldon B. Sosna papers
Tobacco advertisements collection
Provenance
The Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2013.
Smoking -- United States; Tobacco industry -- North Carolina -- History; Tobacco -- Law and legislation -- United States; Tobacco -- Physiological effect; Cigarette industry; Advertising -- Cigarettes -- United States; Deceptive advertising -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Tobacco Company; British American Tobacco Company; Brown & Williamson; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; P. Lorillard Company; Philip Morris Incorporated; R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company; Tobacco Institute (Washington, D.C.)
- 800. Audiovisual Materials, 1964-2010; undated; 1
  - 1. Tobacco Ads of the 60s. London International Advertising Awards (NY). About 50 spots for various brands, including some Canadian. Inventory in box., undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-001)
  - 2. Tobacco Ads of the 70s. London International Adv. Awards (NY) About 50 spots for various brands. Despite label most seem from the 1960s and for North American Airings could be no later than 1971.Inventory in box, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-002)
  - 3. Video Smoke Shop. Video Resources, circa 60 min. Inventory in box., undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-003)
  - 4a. Classic Cigarette Commercials of the 50s and 60s. Video Resources, NYC Inventory in box, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-004)
  - 4b. Copy of 4a., undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-005)
  - 5. "Fear" Cigarette Ads (see 6 and 7 below)- 4 Demo lecture reels of spots edited from "Classic Cig. Comm. of 1950s and 1960s "Fear" and "Relax" includes Walter Winchell news., undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-006)
  - 6. "Macho Males" Cigarette Ads, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-007)
  - 7. "Relax" Cigarette Ads, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-008)
  - 8. Prof. Gerald Gorn's Reel of 1960s cigarette spots, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-009)
  - 9. Cigarette TV Spots (50/60s) from TV's Lost and Found. Inventory in box., undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-010)
  - 10. Tobacco TV Ads: Carter vs. ATC, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-011)
  - 11. "Butt Out: The Life and Death of Cigarette Advertising on TV." A&E, 1992, 45 min. (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-012)
  - 12. Four Canadian Artists Against Tobacco Sponsorship (Canada 1996) (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-013)
  - 13. "Inside Sports" (Canada, TSN, 1993) Players Racing (30 min) (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-014)
  - 14. Business World, Advertising and Canadian Content/ Market Place Ethics, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-015)
  - 15. Tobacco Sponsorship Video Clips from Vancouver and Toronto Indy races, 1994/ History of Tobacco Advertising on TV, A&E, 1992/ CBC Journal, "Selling Smoke," 1991. (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-016)
  - 16. American Advertising Federation, "The FDA Should Honor the First Amendment", 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-017)
  - 17. C. Everett Koop Profile, NOVA, 1991 / CBC Journal, "Selling Smoke", 1991. Copy 1 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-018)
  - 18. C. Everett Koop Profile, NOVA, 1991 / CBC Journal, "Selling Smoke", 1991. Copy 2 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-019)
  - 19. Tobacco in the 3rd World (Philippines), 20/20, 1988. (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-020)
  - 20. Dirty Business, Patrick Reynolds, California dept. of Health Services, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-021)
  - 21. Tar Wars in the Tobacco Arena, Patrick Reynolds, NBC News with Tom Brokaw. (30:00), undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-022)
  - 22a. Pack of Lies: The Advertising of Tobacco, Jean Kilbourne and Rick Pollay, 1992 (38:00) (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-023)
  - 22b. Pack of Lies: The Advertising of Tobacco, Jean Kilbourne and Rick Pollay, 1992 (38:00) (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-024)
  - 22c. Pack of Lies: The Advertising of Tobacco, Jean Kilbourne and Rick Pollay, 1992 (38:00) (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-025)
  - 23. Smokefree, Canadian Cancer Society Campaign, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-026)
  - 25. Tobacco Villain: TV Fiction 1997 from the "Feds" and "The Practice" (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-027)
  - 26. Quit the Lie, ABC Primetime Feb. 23, 1993; Sam Donaldson and Ben Sherwood (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-028)
  - 27. Cigarettes in the News, 1996 CBS Wigand Interview (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-029)
  - 28. Cigarettes in the News, 1994 part 1 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-030)
  - 29. Cigarettes in the News, 1994 part 2 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-031)
  - 30. Cigarettes in the News, USA 1995 / Frontline January 1995/ Confessions of a Tobacco Lobbyist, Victor Crawford on 60 Minutes (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-032)
  - 31. Tobacco in the News, Canada 1995 Ad Ban Fails Tape 1 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-033)
  - 32. Tobacco in the News, Canada 1995 Ad Ban Fails Tape 2 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-034)
  - 33. Never Say Die, ABC News Special June 27, 1996, Peter Jennings (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-035)
  - 34. Showdown on Tobacco Road: Manufactured Epidemic, CBS Nightline 1989 Surgeon General News (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-036)
  - 35. US Surgeon General Press Release re: Youth February 24, 1994 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-037)
  - 36. The Tobacco Wars: International Activities, 60 Minutes, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-038)
  - 36b. The Tobacco Wars: International Activities, 60 Minutes, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-039)
  - 37. The Tobacco Wars: Asian Expansion of US Firms, 60 Minutes, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-040)
  - 37b. The Tobacco Wars tape 2, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-041)
  - 38. "The Smoking Dilemma" Managing Our Miracles, Show #107, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-042)
  - 39. Passing Clouds: The Rise and Fall of Cigarettes, Thames TV 1987, includes US and Canadian examples (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-043)
  - 40. The Making of Break-free, anti-smoking campaign, Health and Welfare Canada, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-044)
  - 41. Anti-Smoking public service Announcements, International Reel 1980s and 90s, TV Bureau of Canada, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-045)
  - 42. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel: EMPOWER, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-046)
  - 43. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel: TRUTH, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-047)
  - 44. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel: WORDS, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-048)
  - 45. STAT--60 years of Deception: Fraud and Deceit in Cigarette Advertising, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-049)
  - 46. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel, Non-smoking spots, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-050)
  - 47. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel, Master, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-051)
  - 48. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel, Master to 1996 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-052)
  - 49. Massachusetts Dept. of Health Historical Reel, Master 1996 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-053)
  - 50a. California Dept. of Health Services: Hooked; Birthday; Unthinkable; Save a Life, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-054)
  - 50b. California Dept. of Health Services: Hooked; Birthday; Unthinkable; Save a Life, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-055)
  - 51. Best of the Best, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-056)
  - 52. UCI Anti-smoking Spots, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-057)
  - 53. AD-Libbing It, Seattle, Washington (12:00), undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-058)
  - 54. Dirty Business, Tony Schwarz (24:00), undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-059)
  - 56. Anti-Billboard project. Larry King Show 1990 and Pollay Interview 6pm news (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-060)
  - 57. Death in the West, 1976 (30:00) (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-061)
  - 58. Pro-Health Public Service Announcements: American Cancer Society, OSH, 1966-1993, also Mississippi "Came" chase (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-062)
  - 59. QUIT TVC Compilation, Australia, 1985-1994, includes Janet Sackman (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-063)
  - 60. Anti-Smoking Public Service Announcements, Washington, DC 1986 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-064)
  - 61. Inoculation Against Cigarette Ads in High school, Dr. Jaffe, Washington DC (5:00), undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-065)
  - 62. Anti-Smoking spots, Ontario Ministry of Health, 1995 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-066)
  - 63. Diamant Collection, Brooklyn commercials, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-067)
  - 64. Presentation reel Backup, 1995 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-068)
  - 65. 36 Cigarette Ads, assembled from TV Lost and Found, 1950s and 60s, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-069)
  - 66. Salem Reel Master, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-070)
  - 67. Confessions of a Simple Surgeon, Pyramid Film and Video, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-071)
  - 68. Tobacco: The Pushers and Their Victims, Part 1 and 2, Pyramid Film and Video, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-072)
  - 69a. The Kent Conspiracy, Australian News and Ads, 1950s, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-073)
  - 69b. The Kent Conspiracy, Australian News and Ads, 1950s, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-074)
  - 70a. L & M reel 1954-1969, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-075)
  - 70b. L & M reel 1954-1969, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-076)
  - 71. RJR Camel Ads, 1935-1944, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-077)
  - 72. Kent Cigarettes, Video Resources (60:00), undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-078)
  - 73. Newport Cigarettes, Video Resources (60:00), undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-079)
  - 74. Chesterfield and L & M Ads, Cipollone Production, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-080)
  - 75. 17 Camel Ads 1950s and 1960s, Burton v. RJR, ATC (Kansas), undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-081)
  - 76. Pall Mall Commercials from Horton v. ATC numbered and edited, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-082)
  - 77. Winston Select, Perfectly Aged Over 2 Years, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-083)
  - 78. CBC re Tobacco (with Pollay) 1997 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-084)
  - 79. 3 programs" 48 Hours Jan. 9, 1997; Teens & Smoking. Lebow Interview. Face the Nation Apr. 12, 1998. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-085)
  - 80. Press Conference Tobacco Deal June 20, 1997. BC Law Broadcast 1 CBC Oct. 1997. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-086)
  - 81. 2 Programs. May 2, 1997. May 10, 1997. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-087)
  - 82. Smoke Screen 1993. Gateway Communications (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-088)
  - 83. 2500025534 Marlboro Advertising Presentation Ken Krom 3/2/87, 1987 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-089)
  - 84. 2500025531 Philip Morris/Marlboro The Marlboro Story, undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-090)
  - 85. 2500025504 Philip Morris Consumer Promotion (19:48), undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-091)
  - 86. Tobacco in the News 1996? Frontline, Alive, 60 Minutes (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-092)
  - 87. Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids. Press Conference. (29:00) 4/3/96, 1996 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-093)
  - 88. Anti-Smoking Maggots :60 & :30 Director's Mix. Jim Edwards., undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-094)
  - 89. 2 Programs. Never Say Die. Peter Jennings ABC 6/27/96. Mike Wallace 60 Minutes 1996 re: FDA. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-095)
  - 90. CDHS Anti-Smoking Campaign Advertising 1998. 6/01/98. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-096)
  - 91. 2 Programs. Canada 1997 Drop Sponsorship. "Kicking the Habit" BC 1997. Smoke Ring--Smuggling. 1997-1998. (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-097)
  - 92. Mass. Public Service Announcements. 6 Programs: Pam Can't Breathe; Krystell; Cigarette With Pills; Transplant; Last Goodbye 20%; My Hope., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-098)
  - 93. WO# 01316. LA County Dept. of Health Services. Movie Trailer. 2 Spots. Equation w/Tag. Breaking the Law w/Tag. 11/12/97, 1997 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-099)
  - 94. 2 Programs. PBS: Smoke in the Eye. CBC: Butting In. U.S. & Canadian versions of a documentary on media reporting of nicotine spiking by tobacco companies. 4/2/96, 1996 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-100)
  - 95. Pack of Lies: The Truth About Cigarette Advertising. Lecture by Prof. Pollay at the Vancouver Institute. 3/15/97., 1997 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-101)
  - 95b. Pack of Lies: The Truth About Cigarette Advertising. Lecture by Prof. Pollay at the Vancouver Institute. 3/15/97., 1997 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-102)
  - 97. Smoke and Mirrors: A History of Denial. Award winning documentary film by the American Lung Association. (75:00). 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-103)
  - 98. Smoke Alarm: The Unfiltered Truth About Cigarettes. Film produced by HBO, Consumer Reports TV, and Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids to educate youth. (30:00). 1996. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-104)
  - 99. "Lobbying For Lives: Lessons From The Front." MediCinema & Canadian Cancer Society. (30:00), undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-105)
  - 100. Benson & Hedges Symphony of Fire. Best Seat in the House. BCTV (July 1999 Promo.) (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-106)
  - 101. Up From the Ashes: The Fight For A New Tobacco Act. MediCinema & Canadian Cancer Society. (53:00). 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-107)
  - 102. Killing (00:30), Landfill (00:30), Conscience (00:30). Arnold Communications & DPH., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-108)
  - 103. From CBC Cover Story, Rick Pollay in B.C. Suit. (10:00). 11/12/98., 1998 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-109)
  - 104. "Tobacco's Other Secret." From 60 Minutes 2000. Whistle blower Les Thompson discusses RJR smuggling operations into Canada. 01/18/00. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-110)
  - 105. A Bill Moyers Special: Free Speech For Sale. Second story in special relates to tobacco and Bill McCain (1998). Segment 20:00. PBS 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-111)
  - 106. RJR Smuggling in Canada. (15:00). 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-112)
  - 107. Camel Trophy Race (30:00) 1998. Player Race Team (20:00). (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-113)
  - 108. "Smoke That Cigarette." White Janssen and Doctors Ought To Care. (51:00). 1988. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-114)
  - 109. Canadian cigarettes on television: includes Du Maurier Open; B.C. Ingredients 1998; RJR--Mafia Smuggling from the program "Fifth Estate." (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-115)
  - 110. PM re: Addiction. A Sheep Video. 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-116)
  - 111. "Friend of the Downtrodden" pool (4) includes "Sam" (We Card) prevention spots. Philip Morris PSAs. 1999. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-117)
  - 112. "Manure." Canadian Cancer Society. (00:00:30)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-118)
  - 113. Nixon v. American Tobacco Co. et al. Witness: Dr. Richard Pollay. December 21, 1998. (00:19:00). (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-119)
  - 114. Evening Exchange 1992. Pollay Interview re: Tobacco Ads. Washington, D.C. (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-120)
  - 115. Cigarette Ads. Benson & Hedges, Parliament, Marlboro, Virginia Slims, Vantage, Raleigh Belair, Kent., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-121)
  - 115. Cigarette Ads. Benson & Hedges, Parliament, Marlboro, Virginia Slims, Vantage, Raleigh Belair, Kent., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-122)
  - 116. Nostalgia Television presents Classic Commercials: The Early Years. Vol. 1. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-123)
  - 117. Nostalgia Television presents Classic Commercials: The Early Years. Vol. 2. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-124)
  - 118. Nostalgia Television presents Classic Commercials: The Early Years. Vol. 3. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-125)
  - 119. Nostalgia Television presents Classic Commercials: The Early Years. Vol. 4. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-126)
  - 120. Forever Yesterday's Commercials. (01:00:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-127)
  - 121. Commercial Best Plus. (01:30:00)., undated (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-128)
  - 122. The Best Classic Commercials From the Fifties & Sixties. Vol. 1. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-129)
  - 123. The Best Classic Commercials From the Fifties & Sixties. Vol. 2., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-130)
  - 124. The Best Classic Commercials From the Fifties & Sixties. Vol. 3. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-131)
  - 125. Comedy Classics presents Commercials from the 50s.(00:36:00). Produced by Parade Video., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-132)
  - 126. Celebrity Commercials. Over 50 Superstars in all! 1987. (01:00:00). (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-133)
  - 127. Johnny Legend presents Commercial Mania. Special Edition. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-134)
  - 128. Classic TV. Sports Heroes Commercials of the 50s & 60s. (00:30:00)., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-135)
  - 129. Kenneth Anger presents "Don't Smoke that Cigarette!", undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-136)
  - 130. Smoke Gets in Your Eyes, produced by Video Yesteryear. 57 minutes., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-137)
  - 131. Mike Wallace. Parliament Pitch., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-138)
  - 132. Shokus Video presents Vintage Television #420-Variety. Includes the Ed Wynn Show (1950), Easter Teleparade of Stars (1955), The Spike Jones Show (1956), and the Jimmy Durante Show (1954). Shows include commercials. Copyright 1985. (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-139)
  - 133. Shokus Video presents Vintage Television #715-Your Hit Parade Holiday Special. Includes the Christmas Show of Dec. 24, 1955 and the New Year's Show of Dec. 31, 1955. Shows include commercials. Copyright 1985. (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-140)
  - 134. "I Love Lucy" 2 Classics w/original Philip Morris commercials. 1) Job Switching (Candy Factory) 2) TV Commercial ("VitaMeataVegaMin") & Laser Disc materials re: Philip Morris etc., undated (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-141)
  - 135. Classic TV presents Cigarette Commercials (Old Gold, Camel, Kool, Pall Mall, etc.). Approx. 60 min. Copyright 1996 Hollywood's Attic. (Box AV5, Video-cassette RL11612-VHS-142)